[Music]
hi everyone welcome back to the channel
this week is another ben and jerry's
flavor now
we had a suggestion on our channel
on one of our previous videos and it was
from
idk fpv whatever that stands for
i don't know first-person
viewer who knows he suggested
or she suggested a ben jerry's
french only flavor now this is
caramel brownie party which is a caramel
ice cream with brownie chunks
cookie pieces and a caramel swirl
so i've never seen it never heard of it
we're just gonna
see if we can recreate it here for you
so stick around and let's see how it's
made
we're going to start with making the
brownies now this is a recipe that i've
used many times before but you can just
use your favorite brownie recipe
whatever that might be
these are the ingredients you're going
to need for it i'll put a list of all
the ingredients you need
in the description below so don't worry
about that to start off with melt your
chocolate and your butter i melt them in
a microwave
once that's fully melted add in your
eggs and your sugar
and beat it together well finally adding
in your dry ingredients
at that point put them in a pan and then
pop them in the oven temperatures and
everything in the description below
the next stage is to make the caramel
now this is quite an easy one
add your sugar into a pan and heat it
all until it melts
there's a whole thing about not stirring
it or stirring it and swirling it and
blah blah blah
do whatever suits you essentially you're
going to use all of this in the ice
cream anyway so it doesn't make any
difference
once the sugar's up to temperature add
your butter combine it well and then
finally add in your cream and just keep
stirring it until it all comes together
nicely
pop it in a container and we'll use it
later on
[Music]
the final making stage of this ice cream
is the actual ice cream base itself
combine all the ingredients apart from
the caramel get the sugar dissolved
add in your stabilizers and your normal
sucrose sugars that's just table sugar
and get it up to temperature once that's
melted add in
60 grams of the caramel you made earlier
because there's stabilizers in this ice
cream you'll need to get it up to about
80 degrees
c once that's ready take it off the heat
and put it in a container
finally add in your cream and that will
bring the temperature down nice and
quick
at which point you can store it in the
[Music]
fridge
once your mix is cooled in the fridge
that could take anywhere up to four
hours
you're going to churn it in your machine
again 15 to 30 minutes depending on what
machine you use
whilst that's churning you can prepare
the cookies and your brownies now the
cookies i've just used oreos and taken
the cream out
but if you have a chocolate cookie that
you prefer you can use those
if you're using a heavier cookie than
oreos you might want to chop them up and
freeze them before you do this
so they don't disintegrate when you
combine it in the ice cream
finally chop up your brownies into
whatever size pieces you like i've done
little
one centimeter cubes here but whatever
size you want is completely up to you
the final stage is the caramel now i
forgot to mention this is a salted
caramel swirl so once i removed the
caramel i was going to use in the ice
cream
i added half a teaspoon of salt and made
sure that was well dissolved
[Music]
so once your ice cream is churned you
can start loading up your tub
now i've used the larger machine here
just because it's a slightly larger mix
but obviously that's just this video
take it out and layer it in your tub as
we do normally i've done
nice large pieces of brownie
loads of cookie and a good helping of
the salted caramel
you might want to ribbon your salted
caramel in but i just went the whole hog
and just
lumped it in once it's all loaded up and
your tub is full
put it in the freezer for two to three
hours until you're ready to eat
[Music]
you
[Applause]
[Music]
there we go scooped up i mean you can
tell straight away that i've
not gone light with the add-ins
i actually do prefer ice creams with
loads of things in there i also like
a good ice cream just on its own but
this flavor it's got
three different add-ins so you just want
to go to town you know what's the point
of scrimping on it because you know that
if you buy the ben
jerry's version there'll be basically
nothing in there you won't be able to
taste any
any of it so if you're making this
yourself you can make it exactly how you
want
i wanted all this in there so let's see
what it tastes like
[Music]
[Applause]
well
i've eaten a lot of ben jerry's over the
years
that's a massive understatement
this is incredible really for a few
reasons
one the ice cream base for this video
was developed by a guy called patrick
svenson
now he runs the ice cream calculator
website he's developed
tirelessly a windows based ice cream
calculator app
if you're new to ice cream or you like
the techie science side of it
i'll put the links below so you can go
and see download it again
windows based you can get it on mac os
or whatever but
it's really good it's a really good ice
cream caramel ice cream is easy to make
but really difficult to get right
this is perfect it's perfect ice cream
texture is amazing taste is amazing
it is really good that aside
the brownies they've just got enough
chew to them so they don't disappear
they keep their body in the ice cream
the caramel sauce
now i know what ben and jerry's like
with a caramel sauce and quite often you
can't even tell it's in there
but here i wanted a good band
and bead of it in there but i also
wanted some chunks because you know when
you've got a good caramel and it freezes
in the ice cream it will melt the moment
it goes in your mouth so you get a
texture
crunch from it and then it starts to
melt it's like having
gooey toffee in your ice cream it's
incredible
and the actual cookie pieces it's just a
little bit extra whether they're needed
i don't know but
if this is really good really good so
idk fpv
thank you very much for suggesting this
flavor it is a
really really good one and this is not
going to be the last time i make it so
recommend you all try this one thanks
very much for watching i'll put some
links to our social media accounts down
below
on the screen come and join us if you
want some flavors made specifically
let us know we'll listen to you and if i
like it then i'll make it
thanks much for watching and we'll see
you next week